

Experienced mobile app developer who has a track record of success creating apps that are both well-received and commercially viable. Skilled with working as a team and incorporating in put into projects. Ability to always look for ways to improve upon an already existing app to keep people downloading it and enjoying it. Strong eye for detail and tenacity to never quit on something until it is perfect.

# **CONTACT**

Civil lines, Rawalpindi Cantt, Punjab, Pakistan

#### Phone:

+(92)311-5944600

#### WhatsApp:

https://wa.me/923115944600

#### Email:

Syednaseebalijafferey@gmail.com

#### LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/imsnat

## **TOOLS/TECH**

#### **Tools:**

- Vs code
- Android studio
- Iira
- Github
- Bitbuket
- Trello
- Selenium
- Appium
- Postman

# Syed Naseeb Ali Tirmizi

(Flutter App Developer)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### > Speed Force Digital Agency (Project Based Onsite Job)

**Team Lead Flutter App Development** 

Nov 2022 —Present

I'm working as a Team Lead Flutter app developer on project based. My key responsibilities in this company are following:

- Using provider, GetX and Bloc state-management
- Social Authentication
- rest API & postman
- work on Ecommerce auction app
- worked on agora based live streaming.
- worked with different payment methods/gateways (Hyper-pay, Strip e, PayPal)
- Manage all of my team on trello and jira.
- Assign task to the team.
- write some unit tests.
- write some widget tests.
- Firebase integration/sqflite/sqlite

### KhasTech Solutions (Onsite Job)

**Team Lead Flutter App Development** 

April 2022 — Nov 2022

I worked as a Team Lead Flutter app developer. Basically this conservice provider and have 188 live apps on google play store.

#### My key responsibilities in this company are following:

- Using GetX state-management framework.
- Using provider state-management
- Social Authentication
- rest API & postman
- responsible for architecture the project.
- write some unit tests.
- write some widget tests.
- Firebase integration/sqflite/sqlite
- Map box and Google maps integration
- Redesign the previous company Android apps into flutter platform.
- Manage all of my team on trello and jira.
- Assign task to the team

#### > Ensorcell Designs & Solutions (Hybrid job)

Sept 2020 — April 2022

(1 year and 9 months)

I worked in this company. Basically this company is service provider.

#### My key responsibilities in this company are following:

- Using GetX state-management framework.
- Using provider state-management
- Authentication
- Facebook login & google sign up.
- rest API & postman requests.
- responsible for architecture the project.
- Manage all of my team on trello and jira.
- Assign task to the team
- Convert old android apps into

- write some unit tests.
- Firebase integration
- Map box and Google maps integration

#### Roles at this company:

• Software Development Team Lead Jan 2022 — April 2022

(5 months)

• <u>Senior Software Engineer</u> Aug 2021 — Jan 2022

(6 months)

• Full stacked flutter developer Sept 2020 — Aug 2021

(11 months)

#### > FreshLocal Solutions (Contact Based)

Feb 2020 — April2021 (1 year and 2 months)

#### **Backend Flutter developer**

I worked as a Back-end flutter developer on contract basis (12 months extended to 13 months) at FreshLocal Solutions Canadian based company. Basically, this company is Software product-based company.

#### My key responsibilities in this company are following:

- Clean code with commenting
- Develop APIs for the team.
- Integrate user-interfaces elements developed by other developers.
- Integrate various APIs from third parties
- Debug existing apps components, fix issues and avoid regressions
- Participate in software architecture, design discussions and code reviews
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Follow the company guidelines and best practices
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Connect company App with stable payment gateways.

> Netsol Technologies Summer intern May 2019 — July 2019 (3 Months)

Pakistan Aeronautical Complex karma) Feb 2019 — Mar 2019
Engineer Intern (6 weeks)

# **EDUCATION**

#### **COMSATS** University Islamabad

MS Software engineering

Grade 3.71/4 | 2021-2023

BS Software Engineering

Grade 3.67/4 | 2016-2020

# Tech:

- Flutter (Dart)
- Git
- Java
- C++
- C#
- Python
- Micro-python
- Arduino code(based on c/c++ code)
- Dart
- Firebase
- SOLlite
- Hadoop
- Kubernetes

# FIELD OF INTERESTS

- Native App development
- Bug testing
- Test planning and execution
- Collaboration and team management
- Use Agile SDLC
- Ai based chatbots.
- Integration of GPT model in apps

# **SKILLS**

- Knowledge of Android/iOS Native App Development
- Experienced in Dart
- Knowledge of Agile and Waterfall methodologies for software development
- Knowledge in SQLite
- Good Knowledge of Git
- Knowledge in Rest API implementation
- Good understanding of Object Oriented Programming & data structures
- Database Design Knowledge (Firebase ,SQL Lite).
- Budget Management
- Strong knowledge in Flutter (Dart, Get X, Provider, localization, Unit test & Widget test, Firebase, Firestore, Animation, caching, Maps, Postman, Swagger)
- knowledge in android development (Java, XML, JSON)

# <u>CERTIFICATIONS/COURSES</u>

- Lean six sigma white belt certification (CSSC)
- Six sigma white belt certification (CSSC)
- SQA Training by the SR. SQA ENGINEER (Employee of Netsol technologies)

# **PIAIC certified in followings:**

- Artificial Intelligence
- ➤ IoT(internet of things)

# **Digiskills certified in followings:**

- > Digital marketing,
- > SEO
- E-commerce management
- Wordpress

#### **IBM certified in followings:**

- Spark level 1
- Hadoop foundation level 1
- ➤ Hadoop foundation level 2
- ➤ Hadoop administration
- ➤ Hadoop data access level 1
- ➤ Hadoop programing level1
- ➤ Big data foundation level1
- ➤ Big data foundation level 2
- Deep learning essential

# Work/Projects

Name of the Apps	Link to the apps	My contributions	Platforms	No. of downloa ds	Rati ngs
Vegetable garden	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.caynax.gardener.c	I developed the whole one	fluttor	101/1	1.5
planner	alendar.notebook https://play.google.com/store/apps	I developed the whole app	flutter	10K+	4.5
Hourly chime	/details?id=com.caynax.hourlychi me	I developed the whole app	flutter	500K+	4.7
Food Former		I develop this are in a calleboration with the team may			
eFood - Express Food Delivery(Play	https://play.google.com/store/apps	I develop this app in a collaboration with the team my contribution in this app is make app stable and proper integration of payment methods and to the available nearest resturants on	g us	5001/	4.2
Yell - Local Businesses Near	/details?id=bd.com.evaly.efood	I develop this app in a collaboration with the teammy contribution in this app makes the Find, contact and review local	flutter	500K+	4.2
You PrestaShop	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.yell.launcher2 https://play.google.com/store/apps	businesses on the app and show the nearest businesses on the map	flutter	500K+	4.4
Delivery Boy App	/details?id=com.velsof.psdeliveryb oyapp https://play.google.com/store/apps	I developed the whole app from scratch with google map.  I develop this app in a collaboration with the team.my	flutter	100K+	4
InstaDoor	/details?id=com.instadoor.custome r https://play.google.com/store/apps	contribution to this app is to make an online supermarket platform with payment method.	flutter	250K+	4.1
Delivery Boy	/details?id=com.instadoor.delivery boy	I developed the whole app	flutter	1K+	4.3
Pacer: Step & Calories Counter	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=charisma.motiondetect orpedometer.steptrackercounter	I developed the whole app	flutter	100K+	4.1
ZoomGrid AI Photo Enhancer	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.appexsoft.zoomgr id.photo.enhance	I develop this app with collaboration of team of backend developers	flutter	10K+	4.7
Live Location & Buddy Tracker	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.charisma.trackassi stant.GPStrackingprofiling.guide	I developed the whole app	flutter	100K+	3.7
Online Greeting Cards Maker	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.charisma.greeting cards.photoframeseditor	I developed the whole app	flutter	100K+	4.6
Story Maker- Insta Story Maker	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.charisma.storyma ker.storyart	I developed the whole app	flutter	1K+	5
VR Movies Collection & Player	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.appex.live.vr.sbs. popular.movies	I developed the whole app	flutter	100K+	3.9
VR Video Converter & VR Player	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.appex.vr.sbs.vide o.converter.player	I developed the whole app	flutter	100K+	3.8
MicroScan: Image to Text Conv	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.appexsoft.microsc an.image.to.text	I develop this app with collaboration of team of backend developers	flutter	1K+	4.6
RingX Audio Cutter & Ringtones	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.appexsoft.ringdroid_android.ringtones	I developed the whole app	flutter	100	4.9
Mqtt Dashboard - IoT and Node-	https://play.google.com/store/apps /details?id=com.app.vetru.mqttdas hboard	I developed the whole app	flutter	50K+	4.8
UbiBot - IoT Console	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.datadudu.ubibot	I developed the whole app	flutter	10K+	4.5